Bello Olaniyan



rafiubello4real@gmail.com



+2348027365891



linkedin.com/in/bello-olaniyan-42626b1b6



https://sanbello.vercel.app/

Summary

Full Stack Developer with over 3 years of experience in web development and as a problem solver who loves facing challenges in my work, I'm excited to be at the deployment phase of my career as a web developer. I love to be on a team that questions possibilities. I've previously been a graphics designer, and bring those skills to my UI development on a team. Independently, I've Delivered 150% on sales targets for 3 consecutive years

Experience



MERN Stack Devekioer

Khristfix Technologies

Jan 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months +)

- Frontend development using React Js, HTML5, CSS3
- · Backend development using Node Js, MongoDB and Express framework
- Prepare Technical Design and Specification documents
- Collaborate with the development team, support, and business on day to day development requests and support
- Prepare documentation and use case scenarios when required
- Leads solution designs, documents architecture proposals and creates high-level design Documents
- · Lead technical solution sessions to ensure that solutions are complete, scalable and are future-Proof
- Helps determine coding standards along with the senior development team and ensures consistent adoption by developers
- Conducts code reviews, mentors and coaches the larger team, provides objective feedback to consultants and development partners to ensure proper execution of projects.

Senior Frontend Developer

FOREMAN TECHNOLOGIES

Dec 2020 - Jul 2021 (8 months)

- · Participate in the entire application lifecycle, focusing on coding and debugging
- Write clean code to develop functional web applications
- Troubleshoot and debug applications
- Perform UI tests to optimize performance
- Manage cutting-edge technologies to improve legacy applications
- Collaborate with Back-end developers to integrate API endpoints
- · Gather and address technical and design requirements
- · Provide training and support to internal teams
- · Build reusable code and libraries for future use
- · Liaise with developers, designers and system administrators to identify new features
- · Follow emerging technologies



Data Analyst

As-Sunnah Enterprise

Jan 2019 - Dec 2020 (2 years)

- · Interpret data, analyze results using statistical techniques and provide ongoing reports
- Develop and implement databases, data collection systems, data analytics and other strategies that optimize statistical efficiency and quality
- · Acquire data from primary or secondary data sources and maintain databases/data systems
- · Identify, analyze, and interpret trends or patterns in complex data sets
- Filter and "clean" data by reviewing computer reports, printouts, and performance indicators to locate and correct code problems
- Work with management to prioritize business and information needs
- · Locate and define new process improvement opportunities

Graphic Designer

Okitech Cyber Cafe

Aug 2018 - Dec 2019 (1 year 5 months)

Overseeing all design projects, from conception to delivery

Designing original pieces, including illustrations and infographics

Reviewing junior designers' work to ensure high quality

Oversee all design projects, from conception to delivery

Design original pieces, including illustrations and infographics

Review junior designers' work to ensure high quality

Refine images, fonts and layouts using graphic design software

Apply typography techniques

Generate ideas to portray concepts and advertise products/services

Increase user-friendliness in digital products

Maintain brand consistency throughout all our marketing projects

Liaise with marketing and design teams to ensure deadlines are met

Stay up-to-date with industry developments and tools

Education



University of Ilorin

Bachelor of Science - BS, Physics 2018 - 2022

Licenses & Certifications

- Problem Solving Certificate HackerRank
- **Certified CSS Developer** HackerRank
- (A) Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp
- Certificate of Completion Frontend Fundamentals Pirple

Skills

Adobe XD • Apollo GraphQL • GraphQL • Microsoft Excel • Microsoft Word • React.js • Vue.js • Node.js • JavaScript • MongoDB

Honors & Awards

Web Design Tutor - NAOSS

Apr 2022

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF KASHERE CHAPTER, GOMBE STATE

Programmer of the Year - NAPPS - National Association of Physics Student Feb 2022

University of Ilorin, Kwara State